Shaun D'Maye

Financial Services Specialist with 20 years experience in multiple disciplines, Certified Agilist. Blockchain - Distributed Ledger Technology - Internet of Things. Certified ScrumMaster

shaun.dmaye@icloud.com

Summary

Experienced Delivery Head with a demonstrated history of working in the financial services industry. Skilled in Operational Efficiency, Procedure Development, Operations Management, Risk Management, Managerial Finance, Business Management and Coverage Support. Strong operations professional currently studying towards a Master of Laws (LLM) focused in International Business/ Trade/Commerce from University of Liverpool. Technology Enthusiast - Blockchain / Distributed Ledger Technology / Internet of Things/ Certified Agilist / Certified Scrummaster

Experience

Head of Proposition Delivery - Business Banking South Africa at Absa November 2015 - Present

Responsible for the implementation of a Proposition Delivery team within Business Banking division, who are accountable for the go to market implementation of Customer Value Propositions and Colleague lead solutions.

Head of Commercial Operations - Business Banking South Africa at Absa January 2016 - January 2017 (1 year 1 month)

Responsible for the commercial transitioning of activity into the Business and Private Banking Operations including commercial contracting, service level management, management information and reporting. Dual role along with the Head: Proposition Delivery.

Transformation Lead - Business Banking South Africa at Absa March 2015 - October 2015 (8 months)

Transformation and Change Lead - Business Banking Division

Service Delivery Lead / Head - Business Banking South Africa at Absa January 2014 - February 2015 (1 year 2 months)

Responsible for the contracting and monitoring of services provided to the Business Banking division by the various Enterprise and COO functions.

Business Manager - Head: Business Banking Coverage at Absa September 2013 - December 2013 (4 months)

Executive Business Management support to the Head: Business Banking Coverage South Africa.

Secondment Assignee at Barclays

March 2013 - September 2013 (7 months)

Secondment to the UK Corporate COO team specifically looking at the development and implementation of the Client Account Planning Tool, on the Corporate instance of Salesforces.

Business Manager - ABSA Capital MidCorporate Segment at Absa

January 2012 - March 2013 (1 year 3 months)

Executive Support to Head: MidCorporate Segment, responsible for Operational Support and Business Management.

Business Manger - ABSA Large Business Banking at Absa

January 2010 - December 2011 (2 years)

Executive Support to the Head: Large Business Banking responsible for Business Management and Operational support.

Operational Risk Manager at Absa

January 2009 - December 2009 (1 year)

Responsible for the implementation and embedment of Operational Risk Management framework within the Large Business and Medium Business Coverage Segments. Concurrently I was responsible for the socialization, implementation and alignment of Group Principle Risk framework and Key Risk Scenario Validation within Business Banking Segment.

Head Of Operations - Large Business Banking (Gauteng East and Mpumalanga) at Absa June 2006 - December 2008 (2 years 7 months)

Regional Leadership responsible for the decentralized processing of all transactions and customer maintenance including Audit and Tax, Financial Transactions, Client and Product Onboarding, Logistics Management, Business Continuity, OHSA, Regional Property Management (5 locations).

Transactional Banker at Absa

March 2005 - June 2006 (1 year 4 months)

Transactional Support to Relationship Executives responsible for Customer Service and product cross sell and penetration based on customer insights and requirements.

Education

University of Liverpool

Master of Laws (LLM) (Currently Studying), International Business/Trade/Commerce, 2016 - 2019 Massachusetts Institute of Technology - Sloan School of Management

Internet of Things, Information Technology, 2018 - 2018

Saïd Business School, University of Oxford

Blockchain Strategy Program, Information Technology, 2018 - 2018

Saïd Business School, University of Oxford

Oxford Fintech Programme, Information Technology, 2017 - 2018

The London School of Economics and Political Science (LSE)

Managerial Finance Certificate, Accounting and Finance, 2017 - 2018

University of Liverpool

PG Diploma in Business Administration, Organizational Leadership, 2013 - 2015

Institute of Bankers (South Africa)

Debt Counsellors Training Program, Regulatory, 2009

College for Advance Christian Education

Advance Diploma of Merit - Ministry, Christian Studies, 2008

Institute of Bankers (South Africa)

Certificate in Banking, Banking, Corporate, Finance, and Securities Law, 2001

Institute of Bankers (South Africa)

Financial Services Certificate, Banking, Corporate, Finance, and Securities Law, 2001

University of Pretoria/Universiteit van Pretoria

Certificate in Marketing Management, Marketing/Marketing Management, General, 2000

Carleton Jones High School

High School/Secondary Diplomas and Certificates, 1993 - 1997

Activities and Societies: Chairman of Student Representative Council

Shaun D'Maye

Financial Services Specialist with 20 years experience in multiple disciplines, Certified Agilist. Blockchain - Distributed Ledger Technology - Internet of Things. Certified ScrumMaster

shaun.dmaye@icloud.com



Contact Shaun on LinkedIn